

Content Designer | Web Designer | Creative Expert

Number: 07751110706

Email: TaihgMcDonagh@outlook.com
LinkedIn: Uk.linkedin.com/in/taihg

GitHub: github.com/taihg Website: Taihg.com

Professional Profile

I am multi-skilled Lead Content Designer located in the West Midlands. I specialize in Creative Design & Content Creation. I have an in-depth understanding of the Adobe Creative Cloud (including Photoshop and Premiere Pro), with a portfolio of successful product launches and ad campaigns aided with my creative prowess. Some of these are available to view on my website at Taihg.com.

I have extensive experience working with HTML5 & CSS3 to create email and website content. Additionally, I possess a thorough knowledge of Content Management Systems including Shopify & WordPress.

I have invaluable experience of the full content creation process from drafting & scripting out video ideas to shooting the videos, audio engineering the sound quality, editing the video and optimizing the content for the relevant social medias.

Education and Qualifications

BSc Business Computing The University of Northampton (2016 - 2019)

(Web Design) The Course involved a mix of Web

Design & Creative Management, with an

Grade: 2:1 emphasis on Mobile First design and

best practices. It provided a great insight into project management principles such as PRINCE2 and the power of data analytics within the creative sector.

Level 3 Computing

Diploma

Bedford College (2014 - 2016) The course laid a solid foundation

for a strong ability within the

Grade: Distinction technical side of computing to fully

comprehend the creative process from start to finish and maximize the quality output of all creative

content.

Professional Experience

2020 - Present Lead Content Designer: LIVEWIRE Telecom Limited, UK

- Comfort coding in HTML5, CSS3 & Bootstrap in a text editor and with editing text embedded in developer code.
- Solid Background using Content Management Systems such as Shopify & WordPress.
- In depth portfolio of successful product launches & ad campaigns with some of the biggest names in the tech industry including Huawei, Xiaomi, realme, Oppo, Vivo, Honor, Mara & many more.
- Created bespoke online store fronts within Amazon to aid in the successful sales boosts of over £1,000,000+.
- Manage the content team and supervised all graphic materials in order to ensure quality and accuracy of the design.
- · Led in the design, development and implementation of content for multiple websites and media channels.
- Created & curated email templates to assist the growth of the company with weekly emails sent out to a group of 10,000+ subscribers
- · Edit, proofread and improve all creative content across the board of web, social and ad content.
- Developed presentational and marketing collateral to assist the B2B side of the business.
- · Provided editorial, creative and technical support to team members and championed a hands-on approach.
- Maintained, developed and communicated the company style guide to ensure consistency with company values and brand.

2019 - 2020

Junior Content Designer: LIVEWIRE Telecom Limited, UK

- Designed numerous graphics (logos, brochures, infographics, presentations, product listings, social media campaigns, advertisements and many more).
- Managed multiple projects under tight time constraints to meet the needs of clients & partners.
- · Recommended and consulted with clients & partners on the most appropriate design techniques for a given task.
- Liaised with outsourced Web Developers & Marketing teams to ensure all content id on brand suitable for the business's needs.
- Promoted content-first design throughout the wider business.
- Handling stakeholder expectations and guiding them through the creative process to ensure the best quality results for both parties.
- Ability to leverage, structure and scale content design as a fundamental part of the UX process.
- Started a user-centric and content-first approach within the business.
- Ensured all content meet quality, regulatory and compliance standards.
- Support project deliveries where needed across the company.

Programming Languages, Technologies & Skills

- O Adobe Photoshop
- O Adobe Premiere Pro
- O Adobe Illustrator
- O Adobe After Effects
- O Audio Engineering (Ableton Live)
- O HTML5
- O CCS3
- O Bootstrap Frameworks
- Omnisend Email Marketing
- O WordPress & Shopify (CMS)

- O MySQL
- O Oracle
- O Microsoft Word
- O Microsoft PowerPoint
- O Microsoft Excel

Personal Profile

Interests include:

When I am not doing something creative on a computer, I enjoy writing & recording music, I am an exgymnast and an avid trampolinist. I enjoy spending time with friends & family and frequently train at the gym. I venture outside whenever possible and you can often find me in the middle of a forest camping, scaling a cliff or somewhere in-between.

I discovered my creative side when I started making YouTube backgrounds and logos on an old Dell Dimension 4700 on Photoshop CS2 at the age of 12, and that creative flair evolved into a love of Content Design as I am now fully immersed into the world of Creative Design & Content Creation.

References

Liz Coulter-smith

Senior Lecturer
The University of Northampton
Liz-coulter-smith@mynorthampton.ac.uk

Julia Vernon

Senior Lecturer
The University of Northampton
Julia.vernon@mynorthampton.ac.uk